Norman Corwin Papers
Norman Corwin Papers
1928-1973
Corwin, Norman, 1910-2011.
21 linear ft.
Papers of the American author, screenwriter, radio and stage dramatist, director, producer. Collection includes production material, including scripts and phonograph recordings relating to Corwin's work as a writer for stage, screen, and radio (1937-1967); correspondence (1937-1965); articles and speeches.
148906
Biographical History
Norman Corwin (1910-2011) was an American writer, screenwriter, producer, essayist and teacher of journalism and writing. His early radio programs included love stories, satire, biography, fantasy, mystery, Bible stories, travelogues, history, media analyses, philosophy, and current events. He has been called America's "poet laureate of radio." On May 8, 1945, his one-hour live broadcast on the occasion of the end of World War II, On A Note of Triumph, drew 60 million listeners; poet Carl Sandburg praised it as "one of the all-time great American poems."
Corwin is also the author of several books, including Holes In A Stained Glass Window (1978) and Trivializing America (1983), and his script for the movie Lust For Life (1957) was nominated for an Oscar. His television credits include his 1971 series "Norman Corwin Presents." In the 1990s he began a new series of radio program for National Public Radio, whose casts have included William Shatner, Jack Lemmon, Charles Kuralt, Martin Landau, Hume Cronyn, and Charles Durning.
As of 2008 Corwin was still very active in his field, writing a monthly column on media, chairing two award committees for the Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, and serving as a Writer in Residence at the University of Southern California's Annenberg School for Communication.
Corwin was recognized many times over his career for his achievements; his awards include a Peabody (1941, the first year they were awarded), the One World Award (1946), a duPont-Columbia Award, and an Honorary Doctorate from Lincoln College (1990). He was inducted into the Radio Hall of Fame in 1993, and in 2006 a documentary film on his life ( A Note of Triumph: The Golden Age of Norman Corwin) won an Academy Award for Best Documentary (Short Feature).
"I have no apology to make for the affirmative tone of these scripts. I am convinced we will get where we want to go. It will be grim en route, but I think there is nothing to be said for cynicism and despair, and everything to be said for getting out and working toward a better world."
-- from the foreword to Untitled and Other Radio Dramas
[Portions of this biographical sketch adapted from Norman Corwin's official website and his USC Annenberg Faculty Page.]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Norman Corwin Papers includes correspondence, manuscripts, printed material, published material, photographs, and more than one hundred and forty recordings, mostly phono discs with a few reel tapes.
As originally donated, many of the packets of material were in numbered envelopes with lengthy typed notes affixed to the front (the author of the notes is unknown). This information has been incorporated into the descriptions given in the inventory below. The notes often reference other envelopes by number; for this reason the numbering has been retained in the folder titles given in the inventory below. So for example,"Guthrie, Woody (463)" indicates that the original envelope was numbered "463" by the donor. The typed descriptions have also been retained and filed in the folder, with the rest of the contents. The donor also assigned numbers to the phono disc recordings, for example LP-1, LP-2, and so on. These numbers have been retained in internal documentation, but are not included in the inventory below. During processing, each recorded item (disc, tape reel, etc.) was assigned a unique identification number (corwin_0001, corwin_0002). Please request recordings using this number.
Correspondence consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence. Much of the outgoing is in the form of carbons. Correspondents include actors and actresses who appeared in Corwin's productions (Joan Crawford, Helen Hayes, Charles Laughton), friends (Elizabeth McCausland, Dorothy Norman), other writers (Stephen Vincent Benet, Dorothy Parker), agents (Cook Brothers, Leah Salisbury), and fans/admirers of his work.
Memorabilia contains of a range of items representing Corwin's career. These include programs from Corwin productions, announcements of his appearances, clippings spanning nearly thirty years, a certificate from Pan American Airways for crossing the International Date Line during his One World Flight, a large scrapbook of Christmas cards received over several years, a few photographs, and more.
Productions of Corwin encompasses all media -- print, radio and film -- and therefore includes addresses, articles and books, operas, poetry, radio programs, stage plays, and much more. Types of material for each production may include correspondence (both internal, related to production issues, and external, such as congratulatory/admiring letters and telegrams), manuscripts, final scripts, photographs, publicity, and recordings. Not all types of material are present for every production.
Productions of others consists of scholarly or artistic output of others that is related to Corwin in some fashion. Included here are interviews of Corwin; papers, dissertations, theses and articles about Corwin and his work; productions by others of Corwin's programs; musical or choral arrangements of his work; and more.
Other Formats Available
A majority of the recordings in the collection have been digitized. A few, due to condition or minor importance, have not.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is divided into series, as described above. Productions by Corwin are subdivided by type and arranged alphabetically by title within each type. Material in each of the remaining series is arranged alphabetically by name or title. Tapes are boxed, discs are shelved individually by ID number. Broken or damaged discs have been rehoused in special boxes.
Related Material
holds the papers of numerous radio and television personalities. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Separated Material
The collection originally contained more than 60 issues of 20th Century Fox Broadcasting News, a weekly newsletter in the form of a script that could be read on the air by movie news commentators or radio station announcers. and numerous issues of the Journal of the Producers Guild of America. These have been transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate these items
Subject and Genre Headings
Popular culture; Radio, television, film; Corwin, Norman, 1910-2011.; Authors, American.; Dramatists, American.; Radio plays, American.; Radio authorship.; Radio producers and directors -- United States.; Screenwriters -- United States.; Articles.; Sound recordings.; Audiocassettes.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Phonograph records.; Photographs.; Radio scripts.; Scripts (documents); Speeches (documents); Tape reels.; Authors.; Dramatists.; Radio producers and directors.; Screenwriters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Norman Corwin, 1966-1970.
Tapes, gift of Barry Best 1971.
Gambill collection of photocopies, gift of Norman Gambill 1973.
Bound volumes of radio scripts, purchased 2014.
Lief correspondence, gift of Donald Lief, 2017.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Abrams, J.J. (233), 1933; 1939,; 1945-1983; family physician (Box 1)
  - Ackerman, Bill, circa 1945 (Box 1)
  - Adler, Edna (451), 1940 (Box 1)
  - Adler, Herbert, 1966; signed and inscribed copy of Adler's play, "Mozart and Mushroom Barley" (Box 1)
  - Aldem, Iris, See J. Walter Thompson Company.
  - Alswang, Ralph (437), 1961; 1965-1966; stage designer and producer (Box 1)
  - Amble, Kjell (231), 1966-1968; professor at San Diego State College (Box 1)
  - American Jewish Congress (425), 1946; 1948,; 1968 (Box 1)
  - Armed Forces, miscellaneous (113), 1942; 1944-1947,; 1955,; 1966,; undated (Box 1)
  - Army Air Force, 1942; handwritten pencilled note by unknown person says, "invitation to be major in U.S. Air Force" (Box 1)
  - Ashworth, Lou Sawyer, 1945-1946; undated; Corwin's assistant (Box 1)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1962-1965 (Box 1)
  - Australia (157), 1946; listener responses to Corwin's broadcasts during visit in September of that year (Box 1)
  - A, miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Bahn, Chester (341), 1939 (Box 1)
  - Baker, Paul (232), 1961-1962; related to the play "Naked to Mine Enemies"; includes printed material from Dallas Theater Center (Box 2)
  - Baner, Skulda (234), 1941-1947 (Box 2)
  - Bardin, Shlomo (230), 1954-1966 (Box 2)
  - Bartok, Peter (235), 1955; son of composer Bela Bartok; relates to project, "Gerald McBoing Boing" (Box 2)
  - Becker, I.S. "Zac" (237), 1940-1948 (Box 2)
  - Ben-Ari, Raikin (236), 1962; 1968 (Box 2)
  - Benet, Stephen Vincent (454), 1942; 1945 (Box 2)
  - Berenberg, Samuel and Fredericka (238), 1941-1944; 1951,; 1957,; 1959 (Box 2)
  - Boroff, George (239), 1956-1959 (Box 2)
  - Boszormenyi-Nagy, Bela, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Bowles, Chester (256), 1960; congressman; includes typescript for Democratic party platform for convention of 1960, written by Corwin (Box 2)
  - Brandeis Camp Institute (257), 1954-1966; undated; correspondence, photographs, newsletters; includes typescript and published version of poem by Corwin (Box 2)
    See also Bardin, Shlomo; Ben-Ari, Raikin; Broidy, Steve
  - Bridson, Geoffrey (258), 1963-1969; correspondence, printed material relating to BBC (Box 2)
  - Broidy, Steve (455), 1959 (Box 2)
  - Brooklyn Eagle, 1940; 1942,; 1945 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Edmund G. "Pat", 1963-1966; Governor of California (Box 2)
  - Buchbinder, Hazel and J.R. (260), 1943-1946; 1965-1968,; undated; friends of Carl Sandburg (Box 2)
  - B, miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Caesar, Irving (261), 1939; 1947 (Box 2)
  - Cheirel, Micheline (262), 1946 (Box 2)
  - Child Study Association of America, 1942; regarding children's radio (Box 2)
  - "Children of Vienna" (448), 1951; regarding film adaptation of novel by Robert Neumann (Box 2)
  - Clune, Frank (344), 1946 (Box 2)
  - Coffin, Tris (263), 1944-1945; 1947 (Box 2)
  - Cohan, James S. (264), 1964; 1969 (Box 2)
  - College Association for Public Events and Services (CAPES), 1967-1969; relates to four lectures Corwin gave at four California colleges (Box 3)
  - Columbia Management of California, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Conkling, Grace Hazard (345), circa 1932?; typescript of poem (Box 3)
  - Conway, Jack (456), 1957; 1960; includes photographs (Box 3)
  - Cooper, Bill and Frank (265), 1965-1968; agents (Box 3)
  - Cooper, Jackie, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Coronet magazine, 1945 (Box 3)
  - Corwin, Samuel, 1945 (Box 3)
  - Cousins, Norman, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Cowan, Tony (266), 1967 (Box 3)
  - Crawford, Joan (268), 1951-1954; undated (Box 3)
  - Crook, J.W. (267), 1928-1931 (Box 3)
  - Croy, Homer (270), 1959; undated (Box 3)
  - Crum, Bartley C. (271), 1944-1948 (Box 3)
  - Curtiz, Michael (484), 1950 (Box 3)
  - Cutting, Dick, 1946-1947 (Box 3)
  - C, miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Daniel, Oliver (483), 1959 (Box 3)
  - Dawson, Ronald, 1947-1948 (Box 3)
  - Delta Kappa Alpha (221), 1968; national honorary cinema fraternity (Box 3)
  - Donohue, Vincent (343), 1958 (Box 3)
  - Dryer, Sherman H., 1939-1943; radio director, University of Chicago (Box 3)
  - D, miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Eames, Owen Whitman (346), 1933 (Box 3)
  - Eichhorn, David Max (272), 1933-1936; 1955-1956,; 1959-1960,; 1967-1968; Rabbi; some relates to "The Story of Ruth" (Box 3)
  - Eleanor Roosevelt Diamond Jubilee Dinner, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Endore, Guy (457), 1965 (Box 3)
  - Engel, Sam (442), 1958-1962; 1968; includes photographs (Box 3)
  - Ernst, Connie (273), 1940-1941; undated (Box 3)
  - E, miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Fabricant, Noah D. (274), 1960-1963 (Box 3)
    See also Hughes, Alice.
  - Feiner, Ben (275), 1945; 1960,; 1962 (Box 3)
  - Feldman, Charles K. (276), 1944-1950; 1968; much relates to Corwin's "Mary and the Fairy" (Box 3)
  - Ferguson, Charles W. (277), 1945; 1947,; 1958-1966; much relates to "Naked to Mine Enemies" (Box 3)
  - Fineshriber, William H. (278), 1942-1959 (Box 4)
  - Finney, Marie, 1942 (Box 4)
  - Forster, Ralph (339), 1943; 1945,; 1951,; 1955-1958; Major, U.S. Army (Box 4)
  - Forsyth, James (449), 1959; most relates to Joshua (Box 4)
  - The Forum, 1946-1948 (Box 4)
  - Frank, Yasha (279), 1940; 1942,; undated (Box 4)
  - Franklin. Sidney A. (280), 1944-1947; 1950 (Box 4)
  - Frederick, John T., 1942 (Box 4)
  - F, miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Garcia-Palacios, Carlos (462), 1949; 1955-1958,; 1962; Deputy Director of United Nations Radio Division (Box 4)
  - Garson, Greer, 1952; letter from Corwin to Garson about H.G. Wells story (Box 4)
  - Goldstone, Nat C. (466), 1958 (Box 4)
  - Golub, Selma, 1938; undated (Box 4)
  - Gordon, Ruth, 1941-1942; 1945,; undated (Box 4)
  - Gordon, William "Bill", Director of Public Relations for Universal-International Pictures
    - Correspondence (240), 1953-1954; 1958 (Box 4)
    - Eulogy, by Corwin (297), 1962 (Box 4)
    - Papers of (241), 1948-1958; small packet of Gordon's personal papers which he gave to Corwin; includes material related to politically-based firing of doctors at Cedars of Lebanon and a visit of Russian journalists to Hollywood (Box 4)
  - Graff, Bob and Ginna, Robert (242), 1962-1964; 1968; Sextant, Inc. (Box 4)
  - Green, Abel, See Variety.
  - Griffin, Lloyd (243), 1938-1942; 1959,; undated (Box 4)
  - Gruber, Ruth (244), 1943-1948 (Box 4)
  - Guthrie, Woody (463), 1940 (Box 4)
  - Guggenheim Foundation, 1948 (Box 4)
  - G, miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Hadassah, 1942; 1961-1962 (Box 4)
  - Hammer, Armand (439), 1963; relates to Corwin's interview of Hammer (Box 4)
  - Harris, Edwin "Ted" and Sandy (347), 1938; 1947,; undated (Box 4)
  - Harwood, Flyn, 1946 (Box 4)
  - Hayes, Helen, 1946; regarding script by Giuliana Taberna (Box 4)
  - Heilner, Irwin, 1963-1965 (Box 4)
  - Hinton, Marilynn, circa 1945-1950; typed information accompanying has incorrect name (Box 4)
  - Holahan, Anne Kerr (248), 1939-1947; undated; includes professional head shot (Box 5)
  - Holloway, Jeanne (381), 1939-1940 (Box 5)
  - Hollywood Museum, See Lesser, Sol.
  - "Homecoming" workshop, 1946 (Box 5)
  - Hotchner, A.E. (249), 1956-1957 (Box 5)
  - Hughes, Alice (250), 1945; 1947,; 1954,; 1959-1960,; undated; columnist for King Features Syndicate (Box 5)
  - H, miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Ivens, Joris (468), 1946 (Box 5)
  - I, miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - J. Walter Thompson Company, 1945-1946 (Box 5)
  - Johnston, Ralph Wardell, 1945; sculptor (Box 5)
  - J, miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Kaufman, Elkin (441), 1943; 1946-1947,; 1956 (Box 5)
  - Kelleher, Anne (460), 1946-1948; Corwin's secretary (Box 5)
  - Kent, Elaine (459), 1938-1942 (Box 5)
  - Kröller Müller Stichting (465), 1955; relating to film version of Lust for Life, about Vincent van Gogh (Box 5)
    See also van Gogh, Vincent Willem.
  - K, miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Lafferty, Perry (438), 1939-1945; 1965; includes photographs (Box 5)
  - Lambert, Jeanne (252), 1935-1936 (Box 5)
  - Lang, Herry H., 1945 (Box 5)
  - "Lassie" series producers (461), 1957; relates to lawsuit over their use of Corwin's "The Odyssey of Runyon Jones" for the episode "The Tooth"; includes synopsis, script, etc. (Box 5)
  - Laszlo, Alexander, See Crawford, Joan.
  - Laughton, Charles (348), circa 1939 (Box 5)
  - Lee, Lawrence, 1947 (Box 5)
  - Lesser, Sol (440), 1961; 1963; relating to Hollywood Museum (Box 5)
  - Lewin, Chuck, 1945; undated (Box 5)
  - Lewis, Henry (447), 1958-1960; agent (Box 5)
  - Lewis, Jerry, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Lewis, Mort Reis, signed and inscribed program from a performance of Lewis' "The Civil War Horse: An Equine Saga" (Box 5)
  - Lieberman, Elias (Mr. and Mrs.), 1937-1938; 1942 (Box 5)
    See also Poetry Society of America.
  - Lief, Donald, 1944 (Box 5)
    Gift of Donald Lief, 2017.
  - Lounsberry, Fred, 1947 (Box 5)
  - L, miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - MacLeish, Archibald (349), 1942; relating to Dorothy Parker (Box 6)
  - Massey, Raymond and Dorothy (350), 1942; 1954,; 1957-1958; relating to Corwin's "The Rivalry" (Box 6)
  - McCausland, Elizabeth (351), 1942; 1946-1947,; 1950; includes copy of poem written by Corwin for her, and printed on her own press; telegram with Corwin's remarks for testimonial dinner (Box 6)
  - McKelway, St. Clair (352), 1963-1965 (Box 6)
  - Meredeith, Jean, 1946; undated (Box 6)
  - Merriam, Eve (253), 1943; includes signed and inscribed copy of poem (Box 6)
  - Monahan, Richard (353), 1932 (Box 6)
  - Moorehead, Agnes (354), 1957-1958; 1963,; 1966-1967,; undated (Box 6)
  - Moross, Jerome (355), 1958; much relates to "Gentlemen, Be Seated" (Box 6)
  - Moses, Charles, 1946-1948; 1955,; undated; most relates to "One World Flight" trip (Box 6)
  - M, miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - National Broadcasting Company (NBC), 1939-1946; 1963 (Box 6)
  - National Council of Teachers of English, 1939-1942; 1945 (Box 6)
  - New York Times, 1945; 1950 (Box 6)
  - Norman, Dorothy, 1946 (Box 6)
  - Nowicki, Matthew, 1945; Polish architect (Box 6)
  - N, miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - O'Flaherty, Maggie, undated (Box 6)
  - Oldfield, Barney (356), 1960-1961; relating to Oldfield's assistance with "White Alice" (Box 6)
  - Osborne, Maybelle Hinton, undated; originally misfiled with Marilynn Hinton (see above) (Box 6)
  - O, miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Pacific Coast Writers Conference (321, 358), 1969; correspondence, printed material (Box 6)
  - Paramount Pictures, 1940; 1945 (Box 6)
  - Parker, Charles (254), 1959-1960; Senior Features Producer for the BBC (Box 6)
  - Parker, Dorothy (360, 360-A), 1939; 1947; includes original typescript of speech for use in Corwin's "Words Without Music" (Box 6)
  - Plummer, Gail (340), 1959-1960 (Box 6)
  - Poetry Society of America (361), 1938; January newsletter (Box 6)
  - Povenmire, E. Kingsley (362), 1966-1967; includes typescript of paper "Forty-six varieties of choric speech," signed and inscribed to Corwin (Box 6)
  - Protestant Radio Commission, 1950 (Box 6)
  - Purdy, Ken (487), 1940 (Box 6)
  - P, miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Radio stations, various, See W[xxx] (various radio stations).
  - Reis, Irving (365), 1939-1942 (Box 7)
  - Rewald, Jack (464), 1955-1969 (Box 7)
  - Rice, Leon, 1945 (Box 7)
  - "Rights and Riots" panels (224), 1968 (Box 7)
  - Riveline, Maurice (335), 1931-1942 (Box 7)
  - Rivkin, Allen, 1961 (Box 7)
  - Robinson, Selma (366), 1930-1933 (Box 7)
  - Rome, Harold (367), 1949; 1957 (Box 7)
  - Rosza, Miklos (368), 1956; 1959-1960,; undated (Box 7)
  - Rotha, Paul (369), 1961-1963; 1966,; undated (Box 7)
  - Ruby. Harry (370), 1960-1963 (Box 7)
  - R, miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - San Diego State College (225), 1966-1968; Fine Arts Festival (Box 7)
  - Schoenfeld, Bernard, 1940; undated (Box 7)
  - Schreiber, Flora Rheta (363, 372), 1966 (Box 7)
  - Schuster, M. Lincoln, 1942; founder of Simon and Schuster (Box 7)
  - "Sexual Revolution" seminars (217, 373), 1967-1969 (Box 7)
  - Siegelaub, Sophie, 1940; 1943 (Box 7)
  - Smart, Stan, 1945-1946 (Box 7)
  - Southern California Choral Music Association (319), 1965 (Box 7)
  - Stevens, George (469), 1948; 1963,; undated (Box 7)
  - Stevenson, Mrs. William (485), 1957-1959 (Box 7)
  - S, miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Taggard, Jenny (472), 1937-1939 (Box 7)
  - Turner, Justin G. (480), 1956-1960; 1964-1965 (Box 7)
  - Tyler, Keith, 1940-1945; 1948 (Box 7)
  - T, miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - University of Chicago, 1947-1848 (Box 8)
  - Unobskey, William (473), 1940; 1946 (Box 8)
  - U, miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Van Gogh, Vincent Willem (474), 1955; includes others as well (Box 8)
  - Variety, 1945; Abel Green (Box 8)
  - V, miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - W[xxx] (various radio stations), 1939-1948; 1960-1962; includes humorous "memo" from staff at WNEC, typescript of Corwin's tribute for WBZ's 25th birthday (Box 8)
  - Wald, Jerry (475), 1943; 1950-1961 (Box 8)
  - Wander, Roy (334), 1953; 1956 (Box 8)
  - Wershba, Joe (476), 1954-1958 (Box 8)
  - Wesley, Marie Hansen (255), 1959; 1969,; undated; includes text of Corwin's speech at her memorial service (Box 8)
    See also Productions: Speeches: Marie Hansen Wesley eulogy.
  - W, miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Y, miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Zachary, George (251), 1940-1942 (Box 8)
  - Zerbe, Marion (477), 1930; includes typescripts of numerous poems (Box 8)
  - de Zirkoff, Bori (Box 8)
    See also Cutting, Dick.
  - Unidentified (Box 8)
- Memorabilia
  - Biographical sketch, undated; 7pp, author unknown (Box 8)
  - CBS Annual Report (320), 1945; makes special mention of Corwin's programs and awards (Box 8)
  - Certificate for crossing international date line (338), 1946; from Pan Am Airways (Oversize 1)
  - Clippings, 1939-1963; undated; clippings about Corwin from newspapers, magazines, etc. (Box 8)
  - "Columbia Presents Corwin" publicity, 1944 (Box 8)
  - "Corwin Presents" proposal package, undated (Box 8)
  - "Four by Corwin" proposal package, undated (Box 8)
  - Interview, Writer's Guild of America, West (199, 211), 1967; Corwin interviewed by Kjell Amble, Roy Madsen, Robert Lee (Box 9)
  - List of episodes for unidentified project, undated; includes titles, stars, rights, production costs (Box 9)
  - Nelson Glueck testimonial dinner (213), 1968 (Oversize 1)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 9)
  - Reading by Corwin (364), 1969; announcement, review (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook of Christmas cards (191), 1940s (Oversize 1)
  - Trips to Panama, London (219), 1962; ticket stubs, receipts, etc. (Box 9)
  - WAIF Whisper Ball program (39), 1955 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous (93, 359, 378, more), 1939; 1962,; 1965; poster from University of California-Santa Barbara, for Corwin lecture series; printed material (Box 9)
- Productions of Corwin
  - Addresses
    - Footnote on One World Flight, 1946; printed pamphlet with text of address given by Corwin at Sydney Town Hall in Australia (Box 9)
    - Footnote on One World Flight, recording, 1946
      Public speech by Norman Corwin at the Sydney Town Hall (Australia) on September 29, 1946. Both Corwin's address and questions from the audience are recorded on this disc. Only Copy extant. The Australian Broadcasting Corporation printed the text of this address in a pamphlet, available to the public. Australian newspapers carried either portions or the full text; copies of these are elsewhere in this collection. Includes a newspaper clipping advertising the conference with Norman Corwin. The label on the disc indicates that the record was made in Sydney by the Australian Broadcasting Commission on 09/29/1946.
      - Footnote on One World Flight Parts 1 and 3 [disc 1 of 4], 09/29/1946; corwin_0092; speech by Corwin; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Footnote on One World Flight Parts 2 and 4 [disc 2 of 4], 09/29/1946; corwin_0093; speech by Corwin; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Footnote on One World Flight Parts 5 and 7 [disc 3 of 4], 09/29/1946; corwin_0094; speech by Corwin; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Footnote on One World Flight Part 6 [disc 4 of 4], 09/29/1946; corwin_0095; speech by Corwin; Lacquer discs/acetates
    - Needed But Not Wanted (193), 1965; article by Corwin (Box 9)
    - Nobel Committee dinner, December 10, 1945